<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DSP App</string>
    <string name="article_title">Choosing Your Words: Harnessing the Power of Communication </string>
    <string name="article_subtitle"> Steps you may choose to take: </string>
    <string name="article_text">
        \n\n 1. Start by becoming clear. Slow down and listen to yourself. Listen to what you
feel and need. \n

       \n 2. Find calm. Wait until you feel less stress and more in control of your emotions so
that you don’t react and communicate in a manner that you will regret. \n
Make “I” statements. \n
\n 3. Describe your observations. State what you see, hear, or notice, in specific
terms without judgment. “I noticed___”, or “I observed___.” \n
\n 4. Share your feeling using a one-word description of the emotion, such as “I feel
sad, scared, worried, or confused.” \n
\n 5. Next, add the need that that you have. “I feel ___ because I need or want ___.” \n


    </string>
    <string name="stress_title">10 signs of caregiver stress!</string>
    <string name="stress_subtitle">Learn to recognize the signs</string>
    <string name="stress_text">
        \n \n 1. Anger \n
    2. Lack of concentration \n
        3. Denial \n
        4. Anxiety \n
        5.Social withdrawal \n
        6. Depression \n
        7. Exhaustion \n
        8.Sleeplessness \n
        9. Irritability \n
        10. Untreatable health problems \n

    </string>
    <string name="working_title">Tips for working caregivers</string>
    <string name="working_subtitle">Your caregiving role may be hard, even overwhelming, but
there are steps you can take that may ease the burden.</string>
    <string name="working_text"> \n \n
        <b> Symptoms of Stress </b> \n
<b> Health </b>: Many working caregivers report health problems, depression, lower productivity on the job,
and lost time at work. If you are frequently distracted at work, emotionally drained, and physically
exhausted, you are not alone. But do not ignore these symptoms. Recognizing them is the first step to
finding solutions.\n

<b> Relationships </b>: You may also find that you have let your social relationships slide. Many working
caregivers cut back on community involvement and spend less time with their own families. If this is
happening to you, make every effort to rekindle friendships and reconnect with your community—for
example, through church or another group. You will be better able to deal with stress if you have a
support network. \n
        \n <b> Steps You Can Take  </b>\n
1. Talk to your employer. Let your manager know your needs related to caregiving. Make it clear that
you are committed to your job and want to find ways to remain productive. \n
2. Resist isolation. Find support in and out of work. Join community caregiver groups for emotional
support, and seek out local resources for help. Take advantage of resources, such as Lotsa Helping
Hands, to coordinate caregiving tasks within your family and support network. \n
3. Take care of yourself so that you can take care of others. As often as you can, get enough sleep. Eat
sensibly, use alcohol in moderation, and exercise. Take a break when the pressure gets too great, even
if it’s just a hot bath or a short walk. Walking with a buddy can cover two needs at once—friendship
and exercise. \n
Know Your Rights
Consult with human resources about what you are entitled to under the law. The Family Medical Leave
Act (FMLA) requires large employers to provide up to 12 weeks of unpaid time off with job protection
when workers must care for a sick or injured parent. Some states have extended this coverage to include
small businesses as well. \n

        <b> Take Advantage of Benefits </b> \n
• Ask about flexible-work options. This could mean a compressed work week or a modified
daily schedule based on need. Job-sharing and telecommuting are also caregiver-friendly
options to explore. Many employers offer flexible work options on a case-by-case basis even if
there is no formal policy. \n
• Contact your Employee Assistance Program (EAP) and find out what support services are
available, such as counseling on reducing stress and managing your time.\n
• Many companies offer access to eldercare referral services through an online database or live
consultants. Such services reduce the burden of having to do distracting and time-consuming
research. \n
• Respectfully share information with your manager or HR on how employers can support
working caregivers. \n
Build a Support System
• Connect with other caregivers at your place of work. It’s likely that some of your fellow
workers face the same caregiving challenges. \n
• Put in a request to human resources to sponsor brown bag lunches or an employee resource
group to help with caregiving issues. Or you could organize your own informal group to meet
during your lunch hour. \n
• Thank your coworkers who take on extra assignments or help you with work projects. They
are part of your community, too. \n
• Make sure your manager knows about your accomplishments at work. This will show you are
able to deal with multiple priorities. \n
• Join the caregiving group on the AARP Online Community to share your story, get support,
and connect with other caregivers. \n



    </string>
    <string name="conflict_title">Resolving Conflicts Related to Family Caregiving</string>
    <string name="conflict_subtitle">The easiest way to avoid caregiving conflict is for a potential care receiver to plan in advance for the
following issues</string>
    <string name="conflict_text"> \n \n
        <b> Healthcare decisions: </b>
• Who should provide care? \n
• What care is needed? \n
• Who should make medical decisions?\n
        <b>Financial decisions:</b> \n
• How should money be spent?\n
• How should investments be handled?\n
• How will concerns over “unwise spending,” etc. be handled?\n
        <b> Living arrangements: </b>\n
• Where?\n
• With whom?\n
• Who decides?\n
• How much independence / supervision is needed?\n
        <b> Communication issues: </b>\n
• What information is needed or missing?\n
• Who has legal authority to access information?\n
• How will information be shared with those who need it?\n
        <b> Family relationship issues: </b> \n
• How should the family deal with sibling rivalries, new spouse or companion, death of a
spouse/caregiver, other changes in the relationship?\n
        <b> Decision – making: </b> \n
• Who should have authority to make decisions?\n
• What input (if any) should others have?\n
• How can decision makers obtain input from the care receiver?\n



    </string>
    <string name="disease_title">Understanding Diseases</string>
    <string name="dementia_text">What can I do to prepare myself now?
These are several things you can do ahead of time, when things are calmer, to get ready to respond to the \n
kinds of events that a natural disaster or an act of terrorism might trigger.\n
Being mentally and emotionally prepared is the best way to reduce the effects of natural disaster or
terrorism. Disaster disrupts our way of life and peace of mind. It can make us feel unsafe and afraid. This
may increase feelings of mistrust and prejudice. You may find you react in different ways to stressful
events. You may change who you will talk to, trust, or where you travel, or how you spend money.
Sometimes feelings of hate towards others arise and lead to violence. This can destroy families and
community life.
Although seniors have great strength from life experiences, planning ahead can help decrease the risk of
harm in an emergency. When planning ahead ask yourself the following questions:
• Do I tire easily?
• Do I need help to see, hear, or walk?
• Do I need to care for another person?
• Do I take daily medication?
Being mentally and emotionally prepared includes knowing:
• What to expect
• When help is needed
• How to get help</string>
</resources>